Molly Jean Bennett

mollyjeanbennett@gmail.com
916-212-7406
Portland, OR

JavaScript Developer

github.com/MollyJeanB
linkedin.com/in/mollyjeanbennett
 www.mollyjeanbennett.com

JavaScript developer skilled in writing, clean, testable code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, vanilla JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. High energy team player who loves rearranging her brain with new technologies.

Skills

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, Enzyme, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, CSS Modules, Sketch App

Back-end: Node.js, MongoDB, Mocha & Chai, Passport, REST APIs, AWS Lambda

Dev Tools: Git, GitHub, Chrome Dev Tools, Heroku, Travis CI

Other: Written technical documentation, linear audio editing (ProTools, Reaper, Hindenburg)

Experience

Full Stack Personal Projects

January 2018 - June 2018

Full Stack Engineer, Chorely - chorely.netlify.com

React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Passport, CSS Modules, Mocha & Chai, Enzyme

- Designed, built, and tested a mobile responsive web app that helps roommates track and gamify household chores
- Created initial design mock-ups and wireframes with Sketch App
- Built components and developed workflow for managing props and state with React and Redux
- Built Express server and designed data models from MongoDB collections
- Iterated and improved UI/UX design with three rounds of user feedback and code review from senior engineers

Full Stack Engineer, NoseMaps - nosemap.herokuapp.com

Node.js, MongoDB, Passport, Mocha & Chai, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS3, HTML5

- Envisioned, created, and tested web app that lets users create geolocated smell diaries inspired by artist Kate McLean's Smell Maps of cities around the world
- Built mapping features with the Google Maps JavaScript API
- Built server and REST API with Express.js and wrote Mongoose data schema

Front-End Developer, Prompt Robot - promptrobot.herokuapp.com

JavaScript, JQuery, CSS3, HTML5, Node.js

- Designed and built responsive web app that generates oddball writing prompts for writers and creative writing teachers by juxtaposing data from randomizing endpoints on the Giphy API and Words API.
- Iterated and improved UI/UX based on user feedback.

Front-End Developer, Park-E-Mon Grow, Women Who Code IoT Hackathon

React, CSS3, Arduino, Adafruit Hardware

- Collaborated with four other developers to build an IoT device and web app over the course of twenty hours at the 2018 Portland Women Who Code IoT hackathon.
- Sketched wireframes for app designed to inspire users to visit and care for public spaces by finding and checking into microclimate monitoring sites throughout their city.
- Assisted with initial setup of prototype IoT device, integrated Adafruit API data into web app, and implemented mapping feature with the Google Maps JavaScript API

Workshop Leader and Teaching Assistant, Thinkful

April 2018 - Present

• Lead weekly two-hour community workshops on JavaScript fundamentals, HTML/CSS, Node, and jQuery to groups of 5-20 students across varying technical skill levels

- Work one-on-one with students on code challenges to bridge gaps in understanding and help them reach "aha moments"
- Assist students with setting up local development environments and working with the terminal

Freelance Writer and Audio Producer

June 2011 - Present

- Author technical guides on topics such as building serverless APIs, working with Node modules in AWS stacks, and using lambda functions for a software startup making a UI for simplified AWS configuration
- Pitch, research, and write food features, essays, lists, and humor pieces for national and local publications including <u>Paste</u>, <u>Atlas Obscura</u>, <u>VICE Munchies</u>, <u>McSweeney's Internet Tendency</u>, and <u>Bustle</u>
- Produce <u>podcast episodes</u> and <u>short videos</u>

Interim Manager, Media Institute for Social Change

May 2017 - December 2017

- Coordinated workshops, homestays, and equipment for a 7-week summer documentary intensive for 12 college students from across the country
- Spearheaded all aspects of production, including scheduling, recording, editing, interviews for The Non-Profit Happy Hour, a weekly radio show on XRAY.FM featuring interviews with Portland non-profit leaders
- Wrote weekly newsletters and managed all social feeds for community of 1,500 donors, instructors, homestay hosts, community workshop participants, and non-profit partners

Personal Assistant, Jean Stein

June 2015 - June 2017

- Served as liaison between author and publishing house during final editorial stages for nonfiction bestseller West of Eden
- Investigated and acquired rights to print obscure historical photographs and document excerpts
- Catalogued transcripts, cassettes, photographs, and letters from five decades worth of oral
 history research on topics ranging from the contemporary art scene in 1960s New York, Cuban
 nightlife in the 1950s, and the rise and fall of Hollywood royalty throughout the twentieth
 century

Program Associate, The Fund for the City of New York

July 2014 - June 2015

- Performed administrative duties and filed financial documents. Assisted with IT as necessary
- Updated internal websites and prepared content for the public-facing site
- Researched and drafted project updates and grant recipient bios for quarterly board meetings

Education

Full Stack Web Development, Flex Program Master of Fine Arts, Creative Writing Bachelor of Arts, Cultural Anthropology

Thinkful Hollins University Colby College